Guide to the Impact Visuals Records TAM.256
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Impact Visuals Records
circa 1975 - circa 2001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Impact Visuals
Morris, David
TAM.256
73 Linear Feet (73 boxes)
Impact Visuals was a New York City-based cooperative photo agency dedicated to social documentary photography. Founded in 1985 by Michael Kaufman, formerly an editor at the Guardian (a radical newsweekly), Impact Visuals operated for 15 years until shutting down in 2001. The bulk of this collection pertains to work orders (including invoices, photocopies of published work, and some correspondence and other related documents). There are also some organizational records, including minutes, notes, and reports.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials donated by David Morris in 2001. The accession number associated with this gift is 2001.069.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Materials are in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical/Biographical Note
Impact Visuals was a New York City-based cooperative photo agency dedicated to social documentary photography. Founded in 1985 by Michael Kaufman, formerly an editor at the Guardian (a radical newsweekly), Impact Visuals operated for 15 years until shutting down in 2001. Impact Visuals was particularly active in documenting the struggle against apartheid, in South Africa and abroad.
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection pertains to work orders (including invoices, photocopies of published work, and some correspondence and other related documents). There are also some organizational records, including minutes, notes, and reports.
Photographers -- United States.; Documentary photography |z United States.; Photojournalism.; Minutes (administrative records); Financial records; Impact Visuals; Morris, David
- Inventory
  - Completed Orders, Jul 1995-Nov 1995 (Box 1)
  - Orders, Jan 1997-Jul 1997 (Box 2)
  - Orders, Jan 1996-Apr 1996 (Box 3)
  - Fax list Notebook Notebook: Photographers' New Work Lists Billing & Tracking Manual PN1 records book for I.V. "New Work" Notebook, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
  - Fax list Notebook Notebook: Photographers' New Work Lists Billing & Tracking Manual PN1 records book for I.V. "New Work" Notebook, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Documents and Files (Box 6)
  - Documents and Files (Box 7)
  - Files & Documents (Box 8)
  - Files & Documents (Box 9)
  - Orders: A-N, Jul 1995-Nov 1995 (Box 10)
  - Completed Orders: R-Z, Mar 1995-Jun 1995 (Box 11)
  - Orders, Sep 1996-Dec 1996 (Box 12)
  - Orders, Mar 1996-May 1996 (Box 13)
  - Orders, Apr 1996-Aug 1996 (Box 14)
  - Invoices: F-K, Pre-1998 (Box 15)
  - Invoices: Pn-Z, Pre-1998 (Box 16)
  - Invoices: A-E, Pre-1998 (Box 17)
  - Invoices: L-Pi, Pre-1998 (Box 18)
  - Orders, 1997-1998 (Box 19)
  - Orders, 1997-1998 (Box 20)
  - Invoices, 1997 (Box 21)
  - Orders, Aug 1997-Oct 1997 (Box 22)
  - Orders, ca. 2001 (Box 23)
  - Orders and Delivery Memos, 1996-1997 (Box 24)
  - Orders, Nov 1997-Dec 1997 (Box 25)
  - Photographer Payments (Box 26)
  - Completed Orders: A-N, Jan 1994-Jun 1994 (Box 27)
  - Completed Orders: N-Z, Jan 1994-Jun 1994 (Box 28)
  - Orders, 1998-1999 (Box 29)
  - Invoices, 1998-1999 (Box 30)
  - Completed Orders: A-M, Jun 1994-Oct 1994 (Box 31)
  - Union (Box 32)
  - "Red Pages" and "Picture Pages", 1986-1994 (Box 33)
  - Tearsheets/Mags (Box 34)
  - Assistant Organizational Member Contracts, Photographer Payments (Box 35)
  - 69 CDs, 29 ZIP disks, and 161 3.5" floppies (Box 36)
  - Mags/Books/Tearsheets "Tearsheets" Newsletter, misc. promo Photography Codes (Box 37)
  - Photographer sales (records) (Box 38)
  - Mags/Books/Tearsheets & Misc (Box 39)
  - 109 CDs, 30 ZIP disks, and 31 3.5" floppies (Box 40)
  - Affiliates – Contracts & Correspondence (Box 41)
  - General Manager/Executive Director mostly FOX (Box 42)
  - 18 CDs, 21 ZIP disks, and 138 3.5" floppies (Box 43)
  - Organization Docs 1) Recruitments Records 2) Coop Policies 3) Portfolio Submissions Log 4) Financial Reports 5) Affiliate Log (1993) 6) New Work Lists (1994), 1993-1994 (Box 44)
  - Memos, minutes, etc (early) (Box 45)
  - Office and Organization (Box 46)
  - Completed Orders, Nov 1994-Mar 1995 (Box 47)
  - Completed Orders, Nov 1994-Mar 1995 (Box 48)
  - Invoices, binder with photographer & client codes, 1993-1994 (Box 49)
  - Invoices, binder with photographer & client codes, 1993-1994 (Box 50)
  - Organizational Docs Executive Director Files (Box 51)
  - Executive Director –VEGA (Box 52)
  - Organizational Docs (Box 53)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1985-1994 (Box 54)
  - Completed Orders: A-Q, Mar 1995-Jun 1995 (Box 55)
  - Orders, Jun 1994-Oct 1994 (Box 56)
  - Organizational Docs (Box 57)
  - Organizational Docs, Invoices, Client Orders, 1995 (Box 58)
  - Completed Orders, 1995-Feb 1996 (Box 59)
  - Organizational Docs (Box 60)
  - Organizational Docs (Box 61)
  - Manuals – Assistant (Box 62)
  - Organizational Docs (Box 63)
  - Organizational Docs & Manuals – Assistant (Box 64)
  - Image Flow, Tearsheets, Organization Office (Box 65)
  - Sales, Affiliates, Pricing, Misc. (Box 66)
  - 4 binders photographer/agency correspondence, applications (Box 67)
  - Photographer/agency correspondence/applications, 1999-2001 (Box 68)
  - Various Documents – including Bylaws (1998), Member Contributor Names & Codes, Tax Returns (1992-97?), Personnel Finances, 1992-1998 (Box 69)
  - Organizations Documents including management committee notes & minutes (Box 70)
  - Photographer Contracts/Police Passes, Financials, Executive Director reports, Misc office docs (Box 71)
  - Photographer Payments, 1989-mid 1990s (Box 72)
  - Patsy Lynch, slides, correspondence, 1996 (Box 73)
  - Mahmood, Nadia (Box 73)
  - Completed Orders: C-Z, Jan 1997-Mar 1997 (Box 73)